Beach, Calder, Anderson & Alden Records 1997.0016
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Beach, Calder, Anderson & Alden Records
1940-1980.
1997.0016
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
63.0 Linear feet
Beach, Calder, Anderson & Alden was a law firm founded in 1919 in Bristol, Connecticut. The collection consists of documents relating to the firm's representation of Bristol Brass Company and E. Ingraham Company.
Beach, Calder, Anderson & Alden.
History
Beach, Calder, Anderson & Alden was a law firm founded by Russell Mink in 1919 in Bristol, Connecticut. The firm specialized in corporate law, estate planning, probate of estates, preparation of wills and trusts, residential and commercial real estate, litigation, labor law, and domestic law. The firm has represented companies throughout Connecticut during its history, including the Bristol Brass Company and the E. Ingraham Company.
The Bristol Brass Company was founded as the Bristol Brass and Clock Company in 1850, the creation of sixteen industrialists from Bristol clock and Waterbury brass interests who hoped to profit in the booming clock industry of Bristol, Connecticut. It was the largest employer in Bristol, with 375 employees by 1880. Its mainstay was the production of brass for automobiles. The company thrived during the years of World Wars I and II, making shell cases for the military but the post-war economy brought a change in the company's fortunes. The amount of brass used in automobiles declined swiftly, and foreign competition eroded the company's clientele. The Bristol Brass Company closed its doors in December 1982, after 132 years as a major part of the Bristol economy.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains the records, agreements, meeting minutes, union records, grievances, and negotiation records of Bristol Brass Company and its subsidiaries, includinh E. Ingraham Company. Subjects in the collection include the C.I.O, Bristol Brass Company, New England Centerless Grinding Company, Accurate Brass Corporation, Sessions Clock Company, McGraw-Edison Company, Commission on Human Rights, Harris & Mallow Products, National Labor Relations, American Arbitration Association, and American Exactron. The collection contains materials from the 1940s through the 1980s, with the bulk of the collection from the 1950s and 1960s. The collection consists of papers relating to the Bristol Brass Company, its administration, and the legal issues it faced during the period.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Provenance and Acquisition
The records were donated by the law firm to the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center in 1987.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to Connecticut labor and Connecticut business. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Administrative Records.; Books.; Clippings (information artifacts).; Correspondence.; Financial Records.; Legal Records.; Transcripts.
- Series I: Inventory
  - Administrative records, correspondence, transcripts, 1940-1942; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 1)
    Scope and Content Note
    subjects include: agreements, arbitration, C.I.O, union records.
  - Administrative records, correspondence,transcripts, 1941-1950; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 2)
    Subjects include: C.I.O, grievances, proposals, union contracts.
  - Administrative records, 1943-1944, 1946-1949, 1950-1952; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 3)
    Subjects include: agreements, union contracts.
  - Administrative records, transcripts, 1941-1950; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 4)
    Subjects include: arbitration, Bristol Brass Co., C.I.O, grievances, miscellaneous, union contracts.
  - Administrative records, correspondence, 1943-1947; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 5)
    Subjects include: agreements, Bristol Brass Co., C.I.O., miscellaneous, union contracts.
  - Administrative records, clippings, 1944-1949, 1951-1956; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 6)
    Subjects include: arbitration, Bristol Brass Co.,Bristol Brass Corp.Bristol Brass Corp. C.I.O, grievances, negotiations.
  - Administrative records, 1951-1957; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 7)
    Subjects include: Bristol Brass Co., grievances, meeting minutes, miscellaneous, negotiations.
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, 1955-1956; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 8)
    Subjects include: Arbitration, Bristol Brass Co., grievances, miscellaneous, negotiations.
  - Administrative records, financial records, 1955-1959, 1960-1968; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 9)
    Subjects include: Bristol Brass Co., grievances, meeting minutes, negotiations.
  - Administrative records, transcripts, 1954-1955, 1957-1959, 1960-1967; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 10)
    Subjects include: by-laws, grievances.
  - Administrative records, correspondence, 1957-1959, 1960-1968; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 11)
    Subjects include: grievances, miscellaneous, negotiations.
  - Administrative records, correspondence, 1966-1967; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 12)
    Subjects include: contracts, grievances, negotiations.
  - Administrative records, reports, 1966-1968; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 13)
    Subjects include: grievances, meeting minutes, miscellaneous.
  - Administrative records, transcripts, 1954, 1961-1969, 1970-1971; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 14)
    Subjects include: arbitration, Bristol Brass Co., meeting minutes, miscellaneous.
  - Administrative records, 1962, 1968-1969, 1970-1975; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 15)
    Subjects include: Bristol Brass Co., contracts, grievances, meeting minutes, New England Centerless Grinding Company.
  - Administrative records, correspondence, 1955,1963-1967; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 16)
    Subjects include: Accurate Brass Corp., negotiations, Sessions Clock Co.
  - Administrative records, books, correspondence, 1955-1959, 1960-1967, 1976-1979, 1980; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 17)
    Subjects include: Accurate Brass Corp., arbitration, meeting minutes, negotiations.
  - Administrative records, correspondence, 1947-1949; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 18)
    Subjects include: by-laws, contracts, negotiations.
  - Administrative records, 1949,1950-1951; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 19)
    Subjects include: arbitration, contracts, meeting minutes, miscellaneous, negotiations.
  - Administrative records, 1948-1949, 1950-1953; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 20)
    Subjects include: arbitration, grievances, meeting minutes, miscellaneous, negotiations.
  - Administrative records, 1947,1950-1953; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 21)
    Subjects include: contracts, grievances, meeting minutes, miscellaneous, negotiations.
  - Administrative records, transcripts, 1951-1955; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 22)
    Subjects include: arbitration, contracts, meeting minutes, negotiations
  - Administrative records, 1954-1955; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 23)
    Subjects include: arbitration, contracts, meeting minutes, negotiations.
  - Administrative records, 1955-1957; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 24)
    Subjects include: arbitration, meeting minutes, miscellaneous, negotiations.
  - Administrative records, 1957-1958; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 25)
    Subjects include: contracts, meeting minutes, negotiations.
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, 1958-1959; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 26)
    Subjects include: arbitration, grievances, meeting minutes, negotiations, pension.
  - Administrative records, galley proofs, 1956-1959, 1960; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 27)
    Subjects include: agreements, contracts, grievances, meeting minutes, miscellaneous, negotiations.
  - Administrative records, clippings, 1958-1959, 1960-1961; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 28)
  - Administrative records, correspondence, 1960-1961; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 29)
    Subjects include: agreements, meeting minutes, negotiations,
  - Administrative records, clippings, 1956-1959, 1962; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 30)
    Subjects include: contracts, grievances, meeting minutes, negotiations.
  - Administrative records, correspondence, legal documents, notes, 1954,1962-1963; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 31)
    Subjects include: agreements, contracts, female grievances, meeting minutes, miscellaneous, negotiations.
  - Administrative records, financial records, legal documents, 1960-1965; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 32)
    Subjects include: arbitration, hearings, meeting minutes, miscellaneous.
  - Administrative records, financial records, 1960, 1964-1965; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 33)
    Subjects include: clocks, contracts, grievances, meeting minutes, negotiations.
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, 1966; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 34)
    Subjects include: arbitration, clocks, meeting minutes.
  - Administrative records, 1965-1968; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 35)
    Subjects include: McGraw-Edison Company, meeting minutes.
  - Administrative records, 1964,1966; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 36)
    Subjects include: grievances, negotiations, retirement claims.
  - Administrative records, correspondence, 1961-1966; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 37)
    Subjects include: agreements, arbitration, renegotiations.
  - Administrative records, correspondence, 1967-1968; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 38)
    Subjects include: contracts, grievances, negotiations, pension amendments.
  - Administrative records, correspondence, design, financial records, transcripts, 1956-1957,1967-1968; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 39)
    Subjects include: agreements, blueprint, contracts, negotiations, pensions.
  - Administrative records, 1966, 1968; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 40)
    Subjects include: grievances, meeting minutes, negotiations, timing devices divison.
  - Administrative records, correspondence, financial records, 1964-1969; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 41)
    Subjects include: bank loans, meeting minutes, miscellaneous.
  - Administrative records, 1965-1966; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 42)
    Subjects include: arbitration, charges, grievances, state labor relations.
  - Administrative records, 1968-1969, 1970; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 43)
    Subjects include: agreements, Commission on Human Rights, grievances, pension negotiations.
  - Administrative records, legal documents, transcripts, 1966, 1970-1971; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 44)
    Subjects include: agreements, Harris & Mallow Products, National Labor Relations, wage negotiations.
  - Administrative records, legal documents, notes, 1965-1967, 1969; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 45)
    Subjects include: grievances, Harris & Mallow Products Inc., McGraw-Edison Company, releases, travelers policies, union exhibits.
  - Administrative records, financial records, legal documents, transcripts, 1965, 1967, 1969, 1970-1971; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 46)
    Subjects include: American Arbitration Association, American Exactron, grievances, negotiations, union exhibits.
  - Administrative records, financial records, 1968-1969, 1970-1971, 1974-1975; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 47)
    Subjects include: agreements, grievances, meeting minutes, miscellaneous, pension board.
  - Administrative records, correspondence, 1968-1969, 1971, 1974; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 48)
    Subjects include: agreements, contracts, meeting minutes, negotiations, pension board, profit sharing & insurance problems.
  - Administrative records, correspondence, 1968-1969, 1970-1972; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 49)
    Subjects include: grievances, pension, profit sharing, tax material.